Bequest of Katharine Kuh
Gift of The Antiquarian Society
Through prior acquisitions of Rowena Marsh Abbott Kate L. Brewster Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Castle Emma B. Hodge Mrs. Potter Palmer II Edward Kendall Rogers Jerome and Irene Schultz and Mr. and Mrs. William Swartchild Jr.
George F. Harding Collection
Signed lower right:  Wm M. Chase.   Bequest of Dr. John J. Ireland
A.A. McKay Fund Income
Signed lower right: Ivan Albright dated lower left: 1974  Gift of Ivan Albright
Gift of Mrs. Herbert A. Vance
Inscribed top of base at left:  Daniel C. French Sc. 1912   Foundry marks on back of base at right:  Roman Bronze Works N.Y.   Gift of Mrs. Philip D. Sang in memory of Philip D. Sang
Inscribed top of base at back right:  Daniel C French   March 1916   Bequest of Arthur Rubloff Trust
Signed lower right:  G. Inness 1894   Edward B. Butler Collection
Signed l. left:  M.S.C. Seville 1873   Bequest of Mrs. Sterling Morton
Signed lower left: E. Potthast  Friends of American Art Collection
Signed lower left:  G. Inness   Edward B. Butler Collection
Signed lower right:  Copyright 1890   By  Frederic Remington   George F. Harding Collection
Gift of Emily Crane Chadbourne
Gift of Elizabeth G. H. Bartol
Gift of Ivan Albright
Gift of Malcolm Kay Kim and Kyle Kamin
Stamped on the rear of the left front leg:  HUNZINGER N.Y. PAT. MARCH 30 1869  Perry and Gertrude Herst Endowment
Gift of Ernest A. Hamill
The Art Institute of Chicago Purchase Fund
Signed and dated lower right on overalls: GRANT   WOOD   1930  Friends of American Art Collection
Gift of Wallace L. DeWolf
Inscribed lower left:  AVGVSTVS. SAINT-GAVDENS MDCCCXCVII   Plaque at top inscribed:  Amor Caritas   Roger McCormick Fund
Gift of Toshiko Takaezu
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. F. M. Fahrenwald
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through Morris and Jane Weeden
Painted in black paint on crest rail underneath upholstery:  3924. Ingersoll   Suzanne Waller Worthy Fund
Gift of G. P. A. Healy
Signed middle right: butterfly monogram  Arthur Jerome Eddy Memorial Collection
Signed lower left:  W. Glackens   Friends of American Art Collection
Signed lower right: IRVINE  Friends of American Art Collection
:  Jaboeuf & Rouard   FONDEURS A PARIS 10 & 12 R DE L'ASILE POPINCOURT   Restricted gift of Brooks and Hope B. McCormick Foundation
Signed lower left: Childe Hassam 1901  On back: c.1901  Walter H. Schulze Memorial Collection
   Restricted gift of Charles C. Haffner III
Art Institute Purchase Fund
Gift of Toshiko Takaezu
Alfred Stieglitz Collection bequest of Georgia O'Keeffe
; engraved around rim of basin:  The Bequest of Mr. John Willis to the Church of Christ in Medford 1755   J. Peter McCormick Fund
Signed lower left:  W. S. Mount 1835   William Owen and Erna Sawyer Goodman Collection
Through prior acquisition of the Charles H. and Mary F. S. Worcester Collection
Gift of Jamee J. and Marshall Field
Alfred Stieglitz Collection gift of Georgia O'Keeffe
Signed lower left:  Arthur W. Dow   Through prior acquisition of the Charles H. and Mary F.S. Worcester Collection
Monogram and date on base:  C F B   15  within a circle  Atlan Ceramic Club Fund
Signed lower left:  Henry Ranger 99   Gift of Charles L. Hutchinson
Gift of Jamee J. and Marshall Field
Restricted gifts of The Antiquarian Society and Mrs. Herbert A. Vance
Signed and dated lower right: Demuth   1921  Alfred Stieglitz Collection
Elizabeth R. Vaughan Fund
Impressed twice on back boards:  HERTER BRO'S ; written in script in pencil on top boards:   N 238 Store   Restricted gift of the Antiquarian Society through the Capital Campaign
in. Marked on the bottom in script  J Preston  Chicago  with a conjoined  J  and  P   Restricted gift of Celia and David C. Hilliard
and  S   Gift of the Antiquarian Society through the Mr. and Mrs. William Y. Hutchinson Fund
Gift of Ivan Albright
Through prior acquisition of the Charles H. and Mary F. S. Worcester Collection
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through Jessie Spalding Landon Fund
Restricted gift of Harry A. Root in memory of Curtis C. Palmer
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through the Mr. and Mrs. Edwin A. Seipp Fund
Signed lower left:  G. Inness 1870   Edward B. Butler Collection
; engraved on the body with the Van Cortlandt family arms  Restricted gift of the Antiquarian Society and Dr. and Mrs. C. Phillip Miller
Wesley M. Dixon Jr. Fund
;  STERLING   H 88 x 15     THE COWELL & HUBBARD CO.   Laura S. Matthews Fund
George F. Harding Collection
Inscribed on back of base: STORRS cast by American Art Bronze Foundry Chicago.  Gift of John N. Stern
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through the Mr. and Mrs. Edwin A. Seipp Fund
Gift of Johnson Wax Company
Through prior bequest of Arthur Rubloff; restricted gift of the Antiquarian Society; Quinn E. Delaney Fund
Mark: chalk inscription on base possibly reading  Bottom ; sticker back left upper corner with printing:  No. Property of Edith Cluett   Helen Bowen Blair Fund
Vance American Art Fund; restricted gifts of Carol W. Wardlaw Jamee J. and Marshall Field; Americana Fund
Roman capital initials in white on either side of original iron lock plate:  H B   Wirt D. Walker Fund
Gift of Charles L. Hutchinson
Mr. and Mrs. Martin A. Ryerson Collection
Quinn E. Delaney and Chauncey and Marion McCormick funds; Wesley M. Dixon Endowment
Restricted gift of Charles C. Haffner III
Through prior acquisitions of David Adler Robert Allerton Ada K. Rew in memory of her parents Mr. and Mrs. Irwin Rew The School of the Art Institute of Chicago and Elizabeth R. Vaughan
Butterfly monogram lower right  Walter S. Brewster Collection
Gift of Toshiko Takaezu
Signed lower left:  Homer 93   Arthur Jerome Eddy Memorial Collection
Right side front edge of base: Frederic Remington Right side back edge of base: Copyrighted 1902 by   Frederic Remington Back side of base: Roman Bronze Works NY  The George F. Harding Collection
Restricted gift of Mrs. Herbert A. Vance
; engraved around rim of dish: a cherub's head and the words  The Legacy of the Honble ISAAC ROYALL ESQ. to the CHURCH OF CHRIST in Medford 1781.   Gift of the Antiquarian Society
Walter H. Schulze Memorial Collection
Gift of Robert Allerton
Through prior gift of Emily Crane Chadbourne
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through Quinn E. Delaney
Alfred Stieglitz Collection gift of Georgia O'Keeffe
signed lower left in wet paint:  SR Gifford '60   Through prior acquisition from the Charles H. and Mary F.S. Worcester Collection
Stamped on bottom in Roman capitals  B. WOODCOCK  in a rectangle conforming to letter shapes  Gift of the Antiquarian Society
Signed lower right:  WINSLOW HOMER -66-   Friends of American Art Collection; Goodman Fund
Signed on reverse of canvas:  Geo. Inness 1848   Gift of Mrs. Edith Kepke MacDonald
Gift of Edward E. Ayer
Inscribed:  Paul Manship c 1916   Friends of American Art Collection
Gift of Toshiko Takaezu
Signed on base of column:  John S. Copley pinx. 1764   The Art Institute of Chicago Purchase Fund
Incised at back of drapers:  T Ball Sculpt Boston Mass 1853 Patent assigned to   C W Nichols   Gift of Richard and Mary L. Gray
Gift of the Antiquarian Society through the Jessie Spalding Landon Fund
Restricted gift of the Graham Foundation for Advanced Studies in the Fine Arts
Quinn E. Delaney fund
Gift of the Johnson Wax Company
Gift of the family of Irene M. Groenier in her memory
Roger McCormick Fund
Signed lower right:  Thomas Cole   1830   Friends of American Art Collection
Signed lower left: Ivan Le Lorraine Albright  Gift of Ivan Albright
Alfred Stieglitz Collection
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Randall Shapiro
Signed lower left:  Cecilia Beaux   A. A. Munger Collection
to top of shade  The Mrs. Maurice H. Mandelbaum Collection
Allan and Sallie Bulley Fund
Signed lower left:  G. Inness 1892   Edward B. Butler Collection
Signed lower right:  Toby E. Rosenthal Munich. 1874   Gift of Mrs. Maurice Rosenfeld
George F. Harding Collection
Restricted gift of Charles C. Haffner III
George F. Harding Collection
Signed 1.r.: Ivan Le Lorraine Albright.  Gift of Ivan Albright
Signed lower left:  Geo. Hitchcock op. XXXV 1-8-8-7   Potter Palmer Collection
Mary and Earle Ludgin Collection
Alfred Stieglitz Collection bequest of Georgia O'Keeffe
Restricted gifts of Charles C. Haffner III Mrs. Harold T. Martin Mrs. Herbert A Vance and Mrs. Jill B. Zeno; through prior acquisition of the George F. Harding Collection
Restricted gift of Jamee J. and Marshall Field the Brooks and Hope B. McCormick Foundation and the Bessie Bennett W. G. Field Ada Turnbull Hertle Laura T. Magnuson and Major Acquisitions funds
Signed lower right by impression in point:  Chas. S. Humphries. 1871   Through prior acquisition of the George F. Harding Collection
George F. Porter Collection
Alfred Stieglitz Collection gift of Georgia O'Keeffe
Signed lower left:  Whistler 63   Gift of Honor and Potter Palmer