Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of Frank C. Springer, Jr. in memory of his wife, Irving Moxley Springer
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Cantor
Emma Harter Sweetser Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of a Couple of Old Hoosiers
Gift of Mrs. John N. Carey
John Herron Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of the Artist
Purchased from the George T. Carleton Bequest
Gift in memory of John P. Frenzel, Sr., by his heirs
Gift of W. J. Holliday, Sr.
Delavan Smith Fund
John Herron Fund
Gift of the Artist
Gift of a Group of African-American Citizens of Indianapolis, April l6, l929
James E. Roberts Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Mrs. Addison C. Harris
Gift of Mrs. Theodore B. Griffith
James E. Roberts Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Purchasd with funds from the Penrod Society and the National Endowment for the Arts
Gift of Mrs. James W. Fesler
Gift of Mrs. John G. Rauch, Sr.
Gift of Anne G. Blackman and Sidney W. Blackman in memory of Freeman E. Hertzel
Gift of the National Coalition of 100 Black Women, Indianapolis Chapter and Mr. Kim Anderson and the Estate of Hermine Floch by exchange
National Coalition of 100 Black Women, Indianapolis Chapter, Estate of Hermine Floch by exchange and James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Susan K. Mallinson
The Indianapolis Chapter of the Links, Inc., Gift of the Friends of American Art by exchange
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art by exchange, James E. Roberts Fund, Mr. and Mrs. C. Severin Buschmann, Jr. Fund
Partial and Promised Gift of Jane and Andrew Paine
John Herron Fund
Gift of a Group of African-American Citizens of Indianapolis
The Robert and Traude Hensel Collection
Gift of Albert J. Beveridge
The Ballard Family Memorial Fund
Gift of John A., Edward W., and Robert B. Adams
Gift of Mrs. John E. Fehsenfeld
Given in memory of Jennie Ray Ormsby by her pupils
James E. Roberts Fund.                                                                                                                               The frame is a gift from Eli Wilner & Company.
John Herron Fund
The Ballard Family Memorial Fund
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
John Herron Fund
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Daniel P. Erwin Fund
James E. Roberts Fund and Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of Lucy M. Taggart in memory of her brother Thomas D. Taggart
Gift of Mrs. Nicholas H. Noyes
Daniel P. Erwin Fund
Gift of Hirschl and Adler Galleries, New York
Gift of Mrs. Gordon C. Cook in memory of Chesley Watkins
Gift of Eleanor Dickson and Otto N. Frenzel
James E. Roberts Fund and Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of S. O. Buckner
Gift of Mrs. Charles P. Mattingly, in memory of Charles Stayton Drake
Gift of Mrs. Vernon E. Hahn
Gift of Anne Marmon Greenleaf in memory of Caroline Marmon Fesler
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. James W. Fesler
James E. Roberts Fund and Emma Harter Sweetser Fund
Gift in honor of Mr. and Mrs. William L. Fortune by their children and Gift of the Alliance of the IMA
John Herron Fund
Gift of the Alliance of the Indianapolis Museum of Art
Gift of Miss Sally Reahard
Gift of Phillip L. Goodwin
Gift of Mrs. James L. Rose in memory of her mother Mrs. William A. Smith
Gift of Mrs. John N. Carey
Gift of Carl B. Shafer
John Herron Fund
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of Mrs. Herman C. Krannert
Gift of George E. Hume
Gift of Booth Tarkington
Gift of Roger Wolcott
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Eugene C. Pulliam
John Herron Fund
Estate of Mrs. James W. Fesler
Gift of Delavan Smith
Gift of the Friends of American Art.
Delavan Smith Fund
Bequest of Delavan Smith
Gift of Evans Woollen, Stoughton Fletcher, Mrs. Edward Daniels, Mrs. E.F. Hodges and Dr. Mary Spink
Gift of the Gamboliers.  The frame is a partial gift of Eli Wilner & Company.
Gift of M. Knoedler & Company through Mrs. James W. Fesler
Gift of Mrs. Nicholas H. Noyes
Gift of the Friends of the Museum
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Henry R. Hope
Discretionary Fund
Gift of Mrs. Lydia G. Millard
The Ballard Family Memorial Fund
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of Eli Lilly and Company
James E. Roberts Fund, Cecil F. Head Art Fund, Mary V. Black Art Endowment Fund, Roger L. Williams Fund
Gift of Paul and Ruth Buchanan
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Kurt F. Pantzer, Sr.
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. NIcholas H. Noyes
Caroline Marmon Fesler Fund
Gift of Dr. Charles Jordan
Courtesy of The Clowes Fund
Bequest of Judge Paul H. Buchanan, Jr.
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John J. Weldon
Gift of the Artist
Gift of Mrs. Henry F. DeBoest
Gift of Mr. Nicholas Noyes
Gift of the Louis Ritman Estate
Gift of Mrs. John N. Carey
Gift of the Gamboliers
Gift of the Artist
Gift of Mrs. Albert J. Beveridge
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of Peter C. Reilly and Dr. Jeanette P. Reilly
Purchased from the Sarah Bella Chambers Calvert Fund as a gift in memory of Mrs. Calvert.
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John G. Rauch, Sr.
Gift of Mrs. John R. Wilson
Purchased with funds from Mrs. John M. Judah, Newton Booth Tarkington, Clarence Wulsin, Stoughton Fletcher, an anonymous donor, and the John Herron Fund
Gift of the Family of Charles H. Brewer and Bessie E. Brewer
Gift of Mrs. Addison Bybee
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of the Newhouse Galleries
Gift of Carl B. Shafer
Gift of Mrs. Albert J. Beveridge
Painted on commission from the Art Association of Indianapolis
Julius F. Pratt Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Robert Brady Adams, John A. Adams, and Edward W. Adams
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Miscellaneous Painting Fund
Mr. and Mrs Julius F. Pratt Fund
Gift of the Woman's Department Club
Bequest of Allen Whitehill Clowes
Courtesy of The Clowes Fund
Bequest of Delavan Smith
Gift of the Artist
Gift of the Lyra Casino Club
Gift of Mrs. Saint-Gaudens
John Herron Fund
Gift of Mrs. George Hume
Gift of Friends of American Art
Emma Harter Sweetser Fund
James V. Sweetser Fund
Gift of Miss Mary Peckham and her sister
Gift of Miss Mary Peckham and her sister
James V. Sweetser Fund
Gift of Josephine W. Duveneck
Gift of Mrs. Horace A. Shonle
Museum Accession
Gift of Mr. David K. Rubins
Estate of Magaret Ann Taylor, Indianapolis, Indiana
Gift of the Sons of J. Ottis Adams
The Orville A. and Elma D. Wilkinson Fund
Gift of Neil D. Skinner
Purchased by subscription
John Herron Fund
Gift of Eva Taggart Parsons
Gift of William George Sullivan
Daniel P. Erwin Fund
Museum Accession
Gift of Mrs. Samuel Richards
Gift of Mrs. Samuel Richards
Gift of Mrs. Samuel Richards
John Herron Fund
Gift of Miss Louise Bybee
Gift of Mrs. William A. Words
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alpheus Snow in memory of Mr. and Mrs. John M. Butler
Gift of Harvey Elam
Gift of the Benjamin Harrison School
Bequest of Delavan Smith
Gift to the Art School by Susan M. Ketcham
Delavan Smith Fund
Gift of the Gamboliers
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of the Artist
Gift of Mrs. Charles C. Kryter in memory of Mr. Kryter
James V. Sweetser Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Henry R. MacGinnis
Gift of Mrs. Booth Tarkington
Gift of Robert Brady Adams, John Alban Adams, and Edward W. Adams
Gift of Mrs. Wood L. Wilson
Daniel P. Erwin Fund
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John Rauch
Gift of Carl B. Shafer
Gift of Eli Lilly
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Eli Lilly
Gift of Frank Churchman
Gift of Mrs. Edward L. Pedlow
Gift of Dr. A. S. Roberts
Gift of Georgia Mattison Coxe
Gift of Mrs. John C. Oesterle (Magaret Marsh Oesterle)
Gift of Miss Gretchen Stark
Gift of Mr. Jack A. Goodman
Gift of Mrs. Jack A. Goodman
Gift of the Sons of J. Ottis Adams
Bequest in memory of Sara C. Allison by her daughter, Cornelia Allison Frazure
Gift of the Sons of J. Ottis Adams
Gift of Kappa Kappa Kappa
Gift in memory of John P. Frenzel, Sr. by his heirs
Gift of Mrs. Henry F. DeBoest
Gift of Evelynne Mess Daily
John Herron Fund
Gift of the Children of Lorena Hunter Zimmer
Miscellaneous Painting Fund
Gift of the National Coalition of 100 Black Women, Indianapolis Chapter
Gift of Dr. Steven Conant in honor of Joan D. Weisenberger
Bequest of Eleanor Harter McFarland of Kalamazoo, Michigan, a former resident of Indianapolis, who studied at the Herron School of Art
Bequest of Eleanor Harter McFarland of Kalamazoo, Michigan, a former resident of Indianapolis, who studied at the Herron School of Art
Gift of Allen B. Schroeder
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of Mrs. Wayman Adams
Gift of Mrs. Albert E. Metzger in memory of Albert E. Metzger
Gift of Mrs. Carrie Chase Roberts
Gift of Mrs. Carrie Chase Roberts
Mr. and Mrs. Julius F. Pratt Fund
Gift of Margaret C. Pratt
Gift of Mrs. Henrik Martin Mayer
The Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Gift of Dr. Steven Conant in honor of Mr. and Mrs. H.L. Conant
Gift of Miss Lena L. Ingraham
Gift of Ann and Joseph Edelman
Gift of Ann and Joseph Edelman
Onya Latour Collection
Gift of Ann and Joseph Edelman
Jacob Metzger Memorial Fund
Indianapolis Museum of Art, Gift of the Indianapolis Chapter of Links
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Francis Bott Duveneck
Gift of Dr. Steven Conant in honor of Mr. and Mrs. H.L. Conant
Gift of Edwin F. Koch, Jr., M.D.
Gift of Mrs. Grant W. Christian
Gift of Mrs. James W. Fesler to the Art School of Indianapolis
Gift of Mrs. Booth Tarkington
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of Mrs. James W. Fesler
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Harris P. Byrd
John Herron Fund
Gift in memory of John P. Frenzel, Sr., by his heirs
Gift of Dr. and Mrs. Goethe Link
Gift of Mrs. Herman C. Krannert
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift to the Art Association through popular subscription
Gift of Rosemary A. Gatewood and Kenneth Gatewood
Museum Accession
Julius F. Pratt Fund
Gift of 15 pupils of McLean Seminary
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Delavan Smith Fund
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Gift in memory of Ann Tyndall Durham
Bequest of Delavan Smith
Gift of Mrs. Addison Bybee
Bequest of Eleanor Harter McFarland of Kalamazoo, Michigan, a former resident of Indianapolis, who studied at the Herron School of Art
Bequest of Eleanor Harter McFarland of Kalamazoo, Michigan, a former resident of Indianapolis, who studied at the Herron School of Art
Gift of Mrs. James Sweetser
Special Fund
Gift of Mrs. John N. Carey
John Herron Fund
Gift of Mrs. Morris Clark
Bequest of Mr. and Mrs. Hugo Fechtman
Gift of Mrs. Samuel Richards
Gift of John J. Weldon in memory of his wife, Jean Dinwiddie Weldon
Gift of Mr. Shirlaw Donnelly Gookins, son of the Artist
Gift of Roger Gould Wolcott
John Herron Fund
Julius F. Pratt Fund
Purchased from Friends of American Art and Friends of Art
Delavan Smith Fund
Gift of the Harrison Memorial Association
Gift of Richard B. Dodson
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of Fifteen Pupils of McLean Seminary
Gift of Miss Mary C. Trees in memory of her father Clyde H. Trees
Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Mary B. Milliken Fund
Gift of the Sons of J. Ottis Adams
The Orville A. and Elma D. Wilkinson Fund
James E. Roberts and Martha Delzell Memorial Fund
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. William H. Ball
Gift of Dr. and Mrs. M. D. Ratner
Gift of the Girls Classical School
Gift of the National Coalition of 100 Black Women, Indianapolis Chapter, the Alliance of the Indianapolis Museum of Art and the Mr. and Mrs. Richard Crane Fund
Partial and Promised Gift of Jane and Andrew Paine
Gift of Allethaire Hendricks and Milton Fisk
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Harry Mallinson
Bequest of Mrs. Floyd Hopper
Gift of the Gamboliers
Lucy M. Taggart Estate
Gift of the Herron Museum Alliance
Gift of Mrs. Paul E. Beem
Gift of Mary B. Milliken
Daniel P. Erwin Fund
James E. Roberts Fund
Bequest of Felicia Meyer Marsh
Gift in memory of John P. Frenzel Sr. by his heirs
William Ray Adams Memorial Collection
Gift of the American Academy of Arts and Letters
Estate of Charles F. Cochran
Gift of the Artist
Julius F. Pratt Fund
Bequest of Julian Wetzel
Estate of Lucy M. Taggart
Gift of Olive F. Whitman and Ray Jennings Morehouse, sister and brother of Lucille E. Morehouse
Gift of Olive F. Whitman & Ray Jennings Morehouse, sister brother of Lucille E. Morehouse
Gift of Katherine J. Darby and Charles C. Darby
Onya LaTour Collection
The Holliday Collection
Gift of Mr. Edward Huber Dunlap in memory of his wife Louise Dunlap
Gift of the nieces and nephews of the artist
Bequest of Ora G. Ethell
Gift of Joan D. Weisenberger in memory of Vera Merz Weisenberger
Gift of Dr. Steven Conant in honor of Mrs. H.L. Conant, Mrs. Ruth Conant, and Miss Joan Weisenberger
Gift of Mrs. Clementine Tangeman
Gift of Mrs. Clementine Tangeman
Mr. and Mrs. Charles E. Ballard in memory of Ed and Dolly Ballard
John Herron Fund
John Herron Fund
Gift of Mrs. Addison C. Harris
John Herron Fund
Gift of Henry Lane Wallace
Gift of Frederick A. Hetherington
Gift of Anonymous Person
Sarah E. Banning Bequest
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Otto R. Lieber
Purchase Fund
Gift of the National Academy of Design, Henry Ward Ranger Fund
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John G. Rauch, Sr.
Gift of Mrs. Adolph Robert Shulz
Gift of Miss Beatrice Zwaan
Gift of Onya LaTour for the Onya LaTour Collection
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
The Holliday Collection
Gift of Mrs. Grace Zelms
Gift of the Artist
Allen Whitehill Clowes Fund
The Ballard Family Memorial Fund
Gift of the Honorable and Mrs. Paul H. Buchanan, Jr.
Gift of Miriam L. Luke, Grandniece of Eusebia A. (Luke) and William C.B. Sewell
Gift of Miriam L. Luke, Grandniece of Eusebia A. (Luke) and William C.B. Sewell
Mr. and Mrs. Charles E. Ballard in memory of Ed and Dolly Ballard by exchange
Bequest of Mrs. John S. Wright
Gift of the Harrison Eiteljorg Gallery of Western Art
Gift of Dr. Steven Conant in honor of Mrs. H.L. Conant
Gift of R. Stanley Lawton
Bequest of C. J. Bulliet
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of Jeanette Wales Blanton
Gift of Mrs. J. J. Thompson
Gift of the Progress Club of South Bend
Gift of Mrs. Reginald Courtis in memory of Miss Priscilla Hazen Hibben
James E. Roberts Fund
Gift of the National Academy of Design from the Henry Ward Ranger Fund
Anonymous Gift
Gift of Albert J. Beveridge, III in memory of his grandmother
Julius Pratt Fund
Gift of Mrs. Belle Mowry Smuck in memory of her husband Walter Smuck
John Herron Fund
Gift of Mrs. C. W. Lord
Gift of Miss Virginia Seipel
A Gift from Mrs. Phyllisann Hibben Courtis to the memory of Louise Douglas Hibben
John Herron Fund
Gift of William Mansur Hume
D.P. Erwin Fund
Gift of the Friends of American Art
Gift of Robert Douglas Hunter
The Ballard Family Memorial Fund
Bertha G. Rush Fund
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Clarence W. long
Gift of Mrs. C. D. Johnson