Purchase from Perls Gallery, New York, on April 6, 1962, by Frank C. Springer, Jr. and Irving Moxley Springer, Indianapolis, for $2,070 Partial gift to the IMA from Frank C. Springer, from 1991 through 2006.
Owned by Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Cantor
From the artist to (Frank Rehn Gallery, New York); purchased by the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 1932 (32.177).
(R.C. and N.M. Vose, Boston); Mrs. John N. Carey; purchased by the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 1929 (29.71).
The artist; Edgar Jetter, Verden; sold through Ben Weinref Ltd. and Sotheby's to Indianapolis Museum of Art 1972
Purchased from the Inaugural Exhibition through the John Herron Fund - probably owned by the estate previously
Judge Alex Simpson Jr. 1919; Rosenbach Galleries Philadelphia...Mr. and Mrs. John G. Rauch Sr. of Indianapolis after 1925; purchased from Mrs. John G. Rauch Sr. 1981
Gift of the artist to the John Herron Art Museum
Purchased from the artist
purchased from Midtown Galleries in New York
Purchased from the Inaugural Exhibition in 1906 by the John Herron Art Fund
Given by the artist in 1910 (10.8).
M.A. Newhouse and Son in St. Louis; Mrs. Helen Ladd Corbett and the Corbett Family of Portland, Oregon; George Calvert fo Indianapolis which was purchased by the IMA.
Mrs. McMorris (mother of the artist Daniel McMorris, close friend of Robert Vonnoh); private collection Kansas City, MO; Berry-Hill Galeries 1971
Washington University, St. Louis 1909 (on loan to the City Art Museum); sold by Kende Galleries in New York May 4, 1945; J.W. Young Art Gallery at Chicago; purchased by John G. Rauch Sr. of Indianapolis; donated to the IMA by Mrs. John G. Rauch Sr.
Purchased from the artist by Freeman E. Hertzel, uncle of Anne Blackman; gift to the museum from Anne and Sidney Blackman through Carol Smithwick
Collection of Derek Beard; ACA Galleries
Thurlow Tibbs, Washington, D.C.; purchased from dealer Craig F. Starr Associates
...Hirschl and Adler Galleries New York; Sloan and Roman New York; purchased by Mrs. Harry Mallinson in 1971; donated to the IMA 2004
Pennsylvania collection; sold at Christie's December 2 1988; Spanierman Gallery of New York; purchased by Jane and Andrew Paine, promised gift to the IMA 1997
Purchased from the artist by the John Herron Art Institute, {1} now Indianapolis Museum of Art, in 1911 (11.1).  {1}Included in the Sixth Annual Exhibition of Works by American Artists at the John Herron Art Institute, 4 December 1910 -1 January 1911, cat. no. 253, and purchased out of this exhibition.  See Art Association of Indianapolis, Indiana, Annual Report, 1911, p. 13.
Bernard Dannenberg Gallery in New York; Mrs. Francis Phipp Mallek from the estate of the artist
Owned by Winifred Brady Adams (wife of the artist); given to the museum by sons of the artist
George Whitney, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1866 (Member Board of Directors, PAFA); (Parke-Bernet Galleries, October 16, 1955); (Berry-Hill Gallery, New York, New York); private collection, New York; (Berry-Hill Gallery, New York, New York); (Parke-Bernet Galleries, October 10, 1969, #2914, #20A Illustrated); (Hamilton Gallery, New York, New York, October 16, 1971); IMA.
Purchased from the artist at the Exhibition of Indiana Art in Tomlinson Hall 1903
The piece was owned by Mrs. Buchner W. Anderson in Cincinnati.  It was purchased by Paul North Jr. in 1954.  The John Herron Art Museum purchased the work in 1954.
The artist; Vose Gallery 1878; IMA 1970
(back to top)Provenance Research is on-going at the Indianapolis Museum of Art, and information will be added to this record as research is completed. Please contact Annette Schlagenhauff, Assoc. Curator of Research, at aschlagenhauff@imamuseum.org with any questions.
The painting was given to Dr. James E.B. Finley by his nephew, Samuel F.B. Morse.  It remained in the family until Finley's great-granddaughter Mrs. E. Vernon Hahn (Maruetta Finley Hahn) donated it to the museum.  The painting is signed by various owners (Mrs. Leighton Finley, Mrs. M.D. Finley, Dr. James E. Finley)
Purchased from the artist by Caroline Fesler; Anne Marmon Greenleaf 1960; donated to the IMA 1977
Purchased from the artist by Caroline Fesler
The piece was purchased from the Robert Rice Gallery in Houston in 1979
Purchased in Italy in the mid-1930s; collection of gaetano Lancellotti, Rhode Island until 1987; sold to the museum through Conner-Rosenkranz
Private Collection; Visalia, Purchased by the IMA from Butterfields and Butterfields in San Francisco, CA in 1997
The piece was first owned by Dr. J.M. Sommerville in 1862.  Bernard Danenberg Inc. of New York sold the piece to the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 1970.
Mr. H. Wheeler Bond purchased the piece from the artist.  Mrs. Edward Carroll Sibley (Mr. Bond's daughter) inherited the piece.  Max Safron of St. Louis purchased the piece.  It was then owned by Dr. Maurice J. Lonsway of St. Louis.  The piece was presented to the John Herron Art Institute of Indianapolis in 1944.
Purchased by Roger Gould Wolcott at an auction in 1951 where the contents of the Lyon's home were sold in Attica.  Records state that it was in the collection of Minnie Parker of Attica.
Mr. Albert Ten Eyck Gardner New York, Cincinnati Art Museum, Hirschl and Adler
The artist; Alfred Stieglitz and An American Place; Mrs. Fesler purchased the piece in 1944; donated to the museum by Mrs. Fesler 1961
Gift to the museum by Delavan Smith
Owned by Mr. James Imbrie of Lawrenceville, N.J. and brought to the museum for purchase consideration.  The painting was originally owned by Judge Carden, a patron of the artist.
Daniel H. Farr; John Levy Gallery in New York 1933; given to the museum in 1952
Gambert and Co. London 1857, M.A. Newhouse and Son St. Louis 1926, Dr. Alva M. Kirkpatrick Indianapolis 1926, Mr. and Mrs. Paul Bilings Columbus 1955, purchased for the Indianapolis Museum of Art
Societ Anonyme, New York, New York; Mrs. H. Edward Dreier, New York, New York; Edith Gregor Haipert, New York (The Downtown Gallery); (Sotheby Park Bernet, Sale#3520, May 16, 1973, catalogue 163 illustrated - Edith Gregor Haipert Collection, Part II and other Property.); Indianapolis Museum of Art, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1973
gift of Lydia Millard
Dr. Alexander Crombie Humphreys [1851-1927], Hoboken, N.J.; inherited by his daughter, Mrs. E.H. Turnbull; (M. Knoedler and Co., New York and Macbeth Galleries, New York); purchased by Edward Ward McMahon in 1932; sold about 1950 to (Hirschl and Adler, New York);{1} purchased by the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 1954 (54.10).  {1} All provenance information contained in a letter from Homer scholar Lloyd Goodrich, dated 29 April 1954, in IMA Historical File (54.10).
Elizabeth Arden commissioned the piece from the artist; Elizabeth Arden salon was purchased by Eli Lilly and Co in 1971; Eli Lilly donated the painting to the museum in 1997
From the artist to Duke Ellington [1899-1974] in 1945; by descent in the Ellington family to Stephen James, Duke Ellington's son in 1974; consigned by James to (Hollis Taggart Galleries, New York) in 2006 (1)  (1) Provenance information supplied by (Hollis Taggart Galleries, New York).
Jonathan Swift, Alexandria, Virginia   William Swift-Patten, Rhinebeck, New York
The artist; Alfred Stieglitz in New York; The Downtown Gallery in New York; collection of Mr. and Mrs. Denman Bellevue WA; private collection; corporate collection; purchased from Alexandre Gallery in 2003 by the IMA
The artist; Blackburn family, San Francisco; Blackburn Estate; (Atelier Dore, San Francisco); (Gerald Peters Gallery, Jackson Hole, Wyoming); Paul H. Buchanan, Jr. [1918-2008], Indianapolis, Indiana; given by bequest to the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 2009 (TR10964).
Donated to the museum by the Louis Ritman estate through Maurice Ritman
Macbeth Galleries in New York, Peter Reilly of Indianapolis; Peter C. Reilly (son) and Dr. Jeanette P. Reilly of Indianapolis
Piece was a gift of the Newhouse Galleries in 1944
Owned by Winifred Brady Adams (wife of the artist); given to the museum by sons of the artist
Purchased from the artist by Friends of American Art and donated to the museum.
The artist to Hirschl and Adler Galleries in New York; IMA 1978
...purchased (from the artiist ) by the Women's Department Club in 1928.  It was donated to the IMA by the club in 1984
The artist;...Mr. and Mrs. Paul Barton of Indianapolis circa 1960; IMA 1975
Collection of Judge Biddle, Logansport and John B. Elam, Indianapolis, Indiana; Mr. Harvey Elam; given to the Indianapolis Museum of Art in 1920.
Owned by Winifred Brady Adams (wife of the artist); given to the museum by the sons of the artist
Purchased from the parents of Mr. and Mrs. Stuart Wilbur circa 1961 in the Midwest; sold to the museum by Mrs. Stuart Wilbur in 1991
Owned by Mrs. Carrie Chase Roberts, sister of the artist
Sold by Newhouse Galleries in New York as part of the Newton Booth Tarkington estate 1952
Purchased from the artist by a group of local patrons for the museum.
The Estate of Robert Henri; (Chapellier Galleries, New York, New York, exclusive representative since 1963 of the Henri Estate, 1972); John J. Weldon and Jean Dinwiddie Weldon, Chilmark, Massachusetts, December 1972; Indianapolis Museum of Art
Purchased by Roger Gould Wolcott at an auction in 1951 where the contents of the Lyon's home were sold in Attica.  Recods state that it was in the collection of Minnie Parker of Attica.
Painted by commission from the sitter's father, Helen Miller McLean and her husband moved to Indianapolis after 1815.  The painting was hung in the McLean Seminary until 1929 when it was donated to the museum by alumni
Purchased from the Graham Gallery in New York 1970
...purchased from Ann Kendall Richards in New York 1971; authenticated by Mr. Klaus Perls of Perls Gallery in New York
The artist, Victor D. Spark New York City, Theodore Stebbins Jr. Northampton, MA 1967, Robert P. Weiman Woodbridge, CO, Indianapolis Museum of Art 1973
Purchased from Max Safron of New York by William H. Ball in Muncie, Indiana; Mr. Ball donated it to the museum in 1977
purchased from Galleries Maurice Sternberg
purchased through Terry Dinten Fass Inc.
Mr. O.J. Wardwell (probably); C.L. Baldwin Esq.; sold through New York American Art Association  Private Collection of Important American Paintings formed by C.L. Baldwin  April 22, 1926; by descent in the family to owner in Connecticut; sold at Christies to the IMA and the Paines at Chirstie's December 4, 1997
Purchased from the Maurice LeClanche collection by Mr. Knoedler for 35,000 francs; Lucy Taggart sent the piece to the John Herron Art Institute to be purchased under the James E. Roberts fund for $3,000
The artist; the widow of the artist; left to the museum by bequest
From the artist to (Frank K.M. Rehn Gallery, New York) in 1943;{1} Mr. and Mrs. Henry R. Hope, Bloomington, Indiana, in 1945;{2} given by them as part of the William Ray Adams Memorial Collection to the John Herron Art Institute (now Indianapolis Museum of Art) in 1947.{3}  {1}See Gail Levin, Edward Hopper: A Catalogue Raisonn, New York, 1995, vol. 3, cat no. O-324, and vol. 4 (CD Rom) reproduces Record Book III, p. 1, indicating it was delivered to Rehn Gallery on 4 January 1943. {2}Ibid., vol 4.  A now detached label in IMA Historical File (47.4) indicates that the painting was purchased by the Hopes out of the 56th Annual American Exhibition held at the Art Institute of Chicago in 1945. {3}Mrs. Henry R. Hope, ne Sarahanne Adams, was the daughter of William Ray Adams.
Miss Violet G. Williams of Cincinnati 1934; Edward H. Dwight of Cincinnati; Indianapolis Museum of Art
The artist to the Sewells; Mrs. William Wallace Luke (wife of Eusebia's youngest sibling); Mrs. Donald Ferguson ( grand-daughter of William Wallace Luke); Gift of Ms Mariam L. Luke of Covington, Indiana (second grand-daughter of William Wallace Luke)
The artist to the Sewells; Mrs. William Wallace Luke (wife of Eusebia's youngest sibling); Mrs. Donald Ferguson (grand-daughter of William Wallace Luke); Gift of Ms Miriam L. Luke of Covington, Indiana (second grand-daughter of William Wallace Luke)
The artist; William Macbeth Galleries; IMA in 1916
The artist; the wife of the artist and his estate; by bequest to R.H.I. Gammell in Boston, Massachusetts 1971; gift to the museum by Robert Douglas Hunter of Boston 1979
The painting was donated to the IMA by John Washington Love's sister, Mrs. Charles D. Johnson